看我手指
Follow my finger.
Adam.
Adam
指给我看...
Show me...
自行车
a bicycle.
看这里
Eyes here.
Adam.
Adam
把自行车指出来
Show me a bicycle.
不 那是球
No,buddy,that's a ball.
Adam 看我
Adam,look at me.
饿了?
Are you hungry?
指给我 午饭想吃什么?
Show me what you wantfor lunch.
还是只顾画线 不看卡片
Still drawing those linesinstead of looking at the cards.
还要橙汁吗?
more juice?
如果他想喝橙汁 得说出来
If he wants more juice,he has to ask for it.
Adam.
Adam
看这里
Buddy,eyes here.
他累了 Dom
he's tired,dom.
遵守时间表的话 本来不会
Wouldn't be if westuck to the schedule.
指出橙汁 孩子
Show me the juice,buddy.
越来越没效果
I think we've reached the point of diminishing returns.
他必须学会提要求
He has to ask for it.
Adam.
Adam
他呛到了
He's choking.
不可能吧 只是汉堡奶酪
That's impossible.It's mac and cheese.
10岁的男孩 不明原因死命尖叫
ten-year-old boy,scscreams for hilife for no reason.
孤独症
He's autistic.
严重的孤独症
Severely autistic.
不说话 不作眼神交流
Can't talk,can't make eye contact.
尖叫也许是他与人交流的方式
Screaming's probably his way of communicating.
看过的三个医生都那么说
And he went to three different doctors who all said just that.
明显不是这次病发原因
Well,so clearly,that can't be the answer.
他的大脑不能过滤信息
His brain can't filter information.
对他感官持续攻击
It's a constant assault on his senses.
要是我也会尖叫
I'd scream too.
或许有医学方面的解释 比如感觉迟钝
Or it's something medical sounding,like dysesthesia.
家长确信儿子出了问题
Parents are convinced that there's something wrong with their son.
什么时候开始相信家长了
Since when did we start believing parents?
相信任何人?
Or anyone?
我们去哪?
Where are we going?
搭电梯
Elevator.
爸爸以前在华尔街工作,妈妈是会计师事务所的合伙人
Dad was on wall street,mom was a partner in an accounting firm.
当孩子确诊孤独症后 就都辞职了
When their son was diagnosed with autism,they both quit.
他们过度保护这孩子 所以害怕
So they're overprotective and scared.
- 有理由排除,- 他们研究这孩子
That's all the more reason to discount-- they study this kid.
听过他尖叫无数次
Heard him scream a million times.
十年来的看护 第一次带他来医院
But in ten years of caring for him,this is the first time they've brought him to a hospital.
急诊室查过咽喉 没有阻塞 正常
E.R.Checked his throat. No obstructions,nothing.
意味着症状只有尖叫 无助于诊断
Which means the only symptom was a scream,which is diagnostic of nothing.
孩子紧抓胸部 血压也上升
Kid clutched his chest,B.P.Was elevated.
也许是胸痛
Maybe there was chest pain.
心脏检查显示正常
E.R.Said the heart was fine.
别这么快忽略疼痛
Don't be so quick to dismiss pain.
到底去哪?
Where are we going?
下去
Down.
粪检 查寄生虫
Stool sample to check for parasites.
血常规 排除感染
Blood culture to rule out infection.
抗核抗体查狼疮
And ana for lupus.
就因为他尖叫?
Because he screamed?
可能是环境应激反应
could also be an environmental reaction.
过敏症
An allergy.
灰尘 小麦 花粉
Dust,wheat,pollen.
- 毒素 吃了什么...,- 去他家 做肺通气扫描
A toxin,or something he ate-- check the house and run a lung ventilation scan.
肺也在胸腔里 对吧?
Lungs are in the chest too,right?
我昨晚跟人约会
I had a date last night.
那女的尖叫
She screamed.
也要花十万给她检查?
Should we spend $100,000 testing her?
当然不用
Of course not.
这里又不是动物医院
This isn't a veterinary hospital.
啸!
Zing!
- 如果觉得这孩子不值得救,- 不是这个意思
Look,if you don't think this kid is worth saving-- that's not what I'm saying.
那可糟了
Well,it's too bad.
本是个好观点
It's a good point.
小孩不过是扁桃腺肿
Kid's just a lump with tonsils.
患孤独症的小孩放到核扫描仪里,会发生什么?
You know what it's gonna be like,trying to put an autistic kid into a nuclear scanner?
你们有的受了
I don't envy you guys.
我要原来的地毯
I want my old carpet back.
稍后再谈吧
we're gonna have to do this later.
有个孩子...
A kid...
在门诊部 出了事故
in the clinic had an accident.
- 通常 别人打电话...,- 要我原来的地毯
Generally,when people are on the-- I wanty old carpet back.
上面沾了血迹
It was stained with blood.
是啊 我的血
Yeah,my blood.
证明毯子是我一部分
Which makes the carpet part of me.
我想要回来
I want it back.
死都要带着它
I want to be buried with it.
不管多愚蠢的事 你说 我就得做吗?
You think you can get me to do anything you want,regardless of how stupid it is?
是我的办公室!
It's my office!
我工作 思考
It's where I work.Where I think.
救人的地方 你才能向有钱人吹嘘,好投资买MRI或低胸上衣
Where I save lives,allowing you to brag to rich people so they'll give you more money to spend on mris and low-cut tops.
我要原来的地毯
I want it back the way it was.
现在的跟原来一样
It's identical to the old carpet.
除了有害的生物垃圾
Except without the hazardous biological waste.
我不会回去,直到每根经久耐用的纤维都归原位
I shall not return to my office until every patented durable micro fiber has been restored to its rightful place.
激昂
Inspiring.
你不想在办公室工作 就在诊厅好了
You don't want to work in your office,work in the clinic.
待不下去 就回家
You don't want to work in the clinic,go home.
没钱给你
And don't get paid.
阿提卡!,(古希腊地区 实行民主政治)
Attica!
阿提卡?
attica?
得过了这一关
He,uh,just needs to finish this level.
只预定了扫描仪半个小时
We only have the scanner up for the next half hour.
- 过时,- 信我
After that-- trust me.
他结束前 别想动他
You don't want to move him until he's finished.
早点作检查 早点回家
Sooner we do this test,the sooner we can get you guys home.
Adam.
Adam
能不能--
Do you think that-- that we--
十分钟 最多了
Ten minutes,tops.
- 如果他脉管紊乱 等不起,- 等不了10分钟?
If he has a vascular disorder,he might not have that-- he might not have ten minutes?
我等不了十分钟
I don't have ten minutes.
不 你不要
No,no,you don't-- want to do that--
Adam.
Adam
遵医嘱 用了通便药 终于能上厕所
I used metamucil like the doctor told me,and finally I was able to use the bathroom.
在马桶里看到我认不出的
But I saw somethingin the toilet I couldn't identify.
包在纸巾里 你能瞧一眼
I-I wrapped itin tissue paper --so youcould take a look.
能让他镇静吗?
couldn't you sedate himor something?
用镇静剂 检测结果就无用了
I could if I didn't wantthe test results to mean anything.
止痛剂 运动
painkillers,exercising.
甚至针灸
We even didthat puncture thing.
都没用 可今早 起床背就不疼
Nothing work then this morning,I get up,my back feels great.
我想得尽快来医院
I figured I'd betterget down here right away.
号外 爸爸抑郁
Big shocker--dad's depressed.
节约时间了
Save your time.
5-羟色胺摄取抑制不会引起胸痛
Ssris don't causechest pain.
每时每刻都安排好了
Every minute of every day is booked.
什么时候吃 睡 玩掌机
When he eats,sleeps,plays his handheld.
没剩下多少生活
Not much of a lifefor them.
自愿组成家庭
They chose to havea family.
孩子什么样 没的选
You don't get to decidewhat your kid's gonna be like.
没人会选这种
Nobody chooses this.
有趣
It's funny.
孩子健全 父母工作
You get a normal kid,the parent works.
孩子特殊 花钱多,父母放弃工作 回后院协助疗程
You get a special kidthat costs more,they quit and turn the backyardinto a therapy circuit.
羡慕残疾小孩
Yes,if onlyyou were handicapped.
能和爸爸共度美好时光
All the good timesyou could've had with dad.
House医生
Hi,dr.House.
叫不出名字的女孩,治好了她爸 为什么还来
Hello,girl whose nameI don't remember,but whose dad I treated,so I don't really know why she's here.
Ali.
Ali
被老爸传染了
Um,I think I caught what my dad has.
鼻子毛病
The rhino thing.
对了
Right.
疼么?
Does that hurt?
有一点
A little.
胸部也有点
It's in my chest,too.
当然
Of course it is.
隔着衣服也行
Kinda had accessthrough the shirt.
但 这也行
But...this'll work.
感觉真好
Feels good.
新泽西什么时候短缺 17岁性冲动男生?
Exactly when did new jersey run out of horny17-year-old boys?
大概五星期前
About five weeks ago.
非常寂寞
It's been very lonely.
通气扫描正常
the ventilation scanwas normal.
该送他回家了
Time to send him home.
现在走不开
Can't leave right now.
恭喜你
Well,congratulations.
你骄傲地拥有鼻子里的东西
You are the proud owner of your very own rhino thing.
鼻病毒- 走不开因为她感冒了?
a rhinovirus-- you can't leave because she has a cold?
因为Cuddy说我不能走
Can't leave becausecuddy says I can't leave.
所有检测正常
All the testsare normal.
别从我这开始
Okay,don't start with me.
我们有支援
We're backed up.
这对大家来说都困难 归功于
I know this is hardfor all of us,but thanks to dr.
Cuddy 医生 我没办公室了
Cuddy,I don't have an office.
不得不在这上班
So I have to work here.
她把你办公室怎么了?
What'd she doto your office?
没法用了
It's unusable.
问题不在肺
So whatever is bothering him,it wasn't his lungs.
房子怎么样?
What about the kid's house?
找到些杀虫剂和酒精 但毒物检测阴性
There were some pesticidesand some alcohol,but the tox screenwas negative.
说明孩子身体没问题
Which means there's nothing physically wrong with this kid.
那个已经讨论过了
We already had that discussion.
做粪便涂片了吗?
We get a fecal smear?
是不是该换个地方?
Should we do thissomeplace else?
不 Cuddy说我得在这儿工作
No,cuddy saysI have to work here.
不 我说的是 你要么在办公室工作,要么在这工作
No,I said you can workin your office or you had to work here.
由于我不能在办公室工作...
And since I can't workin my office...
这就是你的高明规划吗?
is this your master plan?
让医院陷入混乱 直到我更换你的地毯?
Disrupt hospital business until I replace your carpet?
迂回
Devious.
从James Bond(007)的电影里学来的
Saw it in a james bond movie.
粪便涂片!
Fecal smear!
- 跟我说,- 离开这里
Talk to me.-Get out of here.
- 把地毯还给我?,- 不
You'll put back my carpet?-No.
离开这里!
Get out of here!
粪便
Fecal matter.
有样本看吗?
Is there a samplewe can look at?
父母有涂片样本
Parents have the smear kit.
孩子便秘
The kid is constipated.
你尽兴吧
Do what you want.
就是不换地毯
Not replacing your carpet.
抬起屁股 做涂片
Go up his rear and get a smear.
让我想吃面包圈了
Which reminds me,I kinda feel like a bagel.
地毯
Carpets.
需要粪便样本
We need a stool sample.
最好等他玩完那关 是不是?
We should probably waituntil he's finished playing that level,huh?
说真的 他今天好些了
I actually thinkhe's a bit better today.
恢复老样子
He seems more like his old self.
有可能根本没生病
It is possiblethat he was never sick.
我们可能反应过度了
I guess we,uh,could've overreacted.
孩子的肺衬为什么充满积液?
so what makes fluid fill the lining of a kid's lungs?
我们为什么在这里?
Why are we in here?
某种高压攻势么?
Is this some sortof power play?
是
Yeah.
你手指戳孩子屁股 他就胸腔积液
So you stuck your finger in the kid and gave hima pleural effusion.
指甲该剪了吧?
You ever consideredgetting a manicure?
我在他肺部衰竭后 才取大便样
I took the stool sampleafter his lungs failed.
你真对地毯有意见?
Or do you really havea problem with the carpeting?
- 改变让你抓狂,- 说了是高压攻势
Change sets you off-- I said it was a power play.
同意了选项A 就别考虑选项B
Someone answers "yes"to option a,you don't move on to option B.
胸腔积液 得检查心脏是否衰竭
If there's a pleural effusion,we have to rule out heart failure.
为什么现在?
Why now?
为什么现在用高压攻势?
Why a power play now?
我嗅到了软弱的气味
I smelled weakness.
给孩子做一个心回波图
Get the kidan echocardiogram.
有...意思
That'S...funny.
写着"james wilson" 诡异的错误
It says "james wilson." A strange typo.
如果积液是渗出液 用广谱抗生素
If the fluid comes back an exudate,get him on broad-spectrum antibiotics.
谢谢光临
Thank you for coming.
不客气
No problem.
还以为你不介意 借用办公室一会儿
Thought you wouldn't mindsharing offices for a while.
分享故事 情感...
You share stories,feelings...
玩具
toys.
却不能分享办公室
You don't share offices.
这可不太有慧根
That is so not zen.
这是礼物
It was a gift.
有些医生会得到这个
Some doctors get those.
你要早上还是晚上的办公室?
So you want morningsor afternoons?
你无法使cuddy痛苦 就使我痛苦 ,来让我帮你让cuddy痛苦?
You couldn't make cuddy miserable,so you're gonnamake me miserable so I canmake cuddy miserable on your behalf?
对
Yeah.
为什么觉得我能让她痛苦?
What makes you think I can make her miserable?
你擅长这套
Because you're goodat that stuff.
跟你比 小巫见大巫
Oh,I'm nothingcompared to you.
你什么都不扔掉?
Is there anythingyou'll throw out?
一个11岁的病人给我的礼物
That's a gift from an11-year-old patient of mine.
我和她都觉得这是件没用的东西,能让她笑
She and I both knewit was a piece of junk,and that's whatmade her laugh.
- 所以你会留着 直到她,- 她已经走了
So you gotta keep ituntil she-- she already did.
Adam.
Adam
你要保持不动 伙计
I need youto stay still,buddy.
没问题 我稳住他了
it's okay,it's okay.I got him.
开始了
There we go.
好的
Okay.
怎么了?
What?
什么? 他的心脏没问题吧?
What is it?Is his heart okay?
有问题
No.
超声波显示传导异常
Echo suggesteda conduction abnormality.
心电图也证实了
Ekg confirmed it.
还是解释不了渗出
Still doesn't explainthe effusion.
胸腔积液是渗出液
The pleural fluidwas an exudate.
该寻找能同时解释心脏和肺衰竭的病因
We should be looking for something that explains both the heartand lung problems.
感染 寄生虫 癌症
Infection,parasite,cancer.
微生物检测积液中无有机生物,不是感染
Microbiology showedno organisms in the fluid,so forget infection.
这不是高压攻势
It's not a power play.
在门诊部会诊还讲得通
Doing a differential in the clinic makes sense.
惹cuddy生气
Piss cuddy off.
在wilson的办公室也一样
Same thingwith wilson's office.
间接起作用
Works indirectly.
但现在 我们在会议室
But now,we are in office space.
因为你不想呆在自己的办公室
Because you don't want to be in your own office.
就是说这和cuddy没关系
Which means this has nothingto do with cuddy.
你真的迷恋你的地毯
You really are obsessedwith your carpets.
- 也就是,- 你们在这里做什么?
Which means--what are you doing here?
我在2:00到3:00预定了会议室
I have this room booked from 2:00 to 3:00.
东部时间2点
Oh,2:00 east coast time.
还以为你指太平洋时间
I thought you meant pacific.
就是...
Which is...
我真有点傻
stupid of me,I guess.
寄生虫检测如何?
What about parasites?
大便采样显示为阴性
Stool samplewas negative.
到2:00了
It's 2:00.
好吧 我们该走了
Oh,well,we should go,then.
只剩下癌症
That just leaves cancer.
做肺部活检
Get a lung biopsy.
做肺部活检 让小孩戴面罩 就得花半小时
It took a half an hourto get the mask on the kid for the lung scan.
真可怜
Oh,I'm sorry.
你有别的地方要去吗?
Was there somewhereyou needed to be?
House.
House
可以谈谈么?
Can we talk?
- 地毯?,- 别想
Carpet?-Never.
那没什么好谈的
Nothing to talk about.
你女友今天打了15次门诊电话找你
Your girlfriend called the clinic 15 times looking for you today.
很多要商量
Lot to discuss.
- 瓷器花式,- house.
China patterns--house.
她跟着你不放
She's a stalker.
是的
Right.
就不能是她觉得我有趣
Couldn't be thatshe finds me interesting.
有吸引力
Attractive.
非得是她疯了
Has to bethat she's insane.
她找了你15次
She's called you 15 times.
你母亲都不会对你那么感兴趣
Your mother's notthat interested in you.
要是她对我多关心 我现在会更好
Well,maybe I'd bebetter adjusted if she was.
- 已经通知保安了 ,- 和地毯有关么?
I'm notifying security.-Is this about the carpet?
夺走了我所有的乐子 我就会投降?
You think I'll back offif you block all my fun?
你最好不要乐在其中
You better not be having fun.
我觉得有意思
I'm having fun.
没有和她发生关系
I'm not having sex.
- 她很危险 - 她不危险
She's dangerous.-She's not dangerous.
她很漂亮
She's pretty.
男人都是傻瓜
Men are stupid.
到此为止 都同意你
I'm with you so far.
我通知了保安
I'm notifying security.
放她一马
Oh,give her a break.
她不危险 她...
She's not dangerous,she'S...
有眼光
insightful.
你不能阻止我们的爱!
You can't stop our love!
你时间么?
Hey,you got a minute?
有
Yeah.
十岁的病童 胸腔积液 传导异常,心脏没有衰竭
We have a ten-year-oldwith pleural effusion and conduction abnormalitybut no heart failure.
胸膜液中含有蛋白质么?
Was there a protein in the pleural fluid?
有 猜可能是癌症
Yeah,that's whywe're thinking cancer.
可能是非何杰金氏淋巴瘤
Non-hodgkin's,probably.
要做一个肺部活检
So we want to doa lung biopsy.
肺活检结果通常都是阴性
Lung biopsies usuallycome back negative.
对臂下的淋巴结做活检
So biopsy a lymph node under the arm.
这正是肿瘤学家要做的 对么?
That's probably somethingan oncologist should do,right?
没什么棘手
There's nothing real tricky to it.
就是个活检
It's a biopsy.
为了安全起见 介意么?
Still,just to be safe,you mind?
看在主的份上!
For the love of god!
有没有人让这个小孩闭嘴?
Can't somebody shut that kid up?
有人在这附近工作
Some people are tryingto work around here.
为什么不给他一个泰迪熊 或别的?
Why don't you show hima teddy bear or something?
你是谁?
Who are you?
你永远不会送礼物的人
Somebody you'll neversend a a gift to.
这是House医生
This is dr.House.
你儿子的医生
Your son's doctor.
重要的检查 快
High test,please.
嘿 嘿!
Hey,hey,hey,hey!
维柯丁磕完了?
Out of vicodin?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
吃红莓
Eating the red berries.
他信任你
He trusted you.
不 那不是信任
No,that wasn't trust.
那是...
That was...
自我保护
self-preservation.
不
No.
太厉害了
That was huge.
就像是一次谈话
It was like a conversation.
一只猴子不敢吃红莓,直到他看见另一猴子在吃
A monk-- a monkey's afraidto eat the red berries until he seesanother monkey eat them.
猴子有样 学样
Monkey see,monkey do.
如此而已
That's all it was.
孩子的情况没有改善
Your kid's stilljust as messed up as when we admitted him.
有感觉
That was sensitive.
你的头发真漂亮
You have pretty hair.
每对父母都得抱着希望
Hope is all those parents have going for them.
不 希望让他们痛苦
No,hope is what's making them miserable.
该做的是弄一只考克斯班尼犬
What they should dois get a cocker spaniel.
狗会看着他们的眼睛
A dog would look themin the eye.
高兴的时候 摇尾巴
Wag his tailwhen he's happy.
舔人的脸 表达爱
Lick their face,show them love.
要一个正常的孩子 有什么错?
Is it so wrong for themto want to have a normal child?
想变正常 这很正常
It's normal to wantto be normal.
说话就像圈子里真正的女皇
Spoken likea true circle queen.
有优越感的浅薄白人划出清晰的小圈子
See,skinny,socially privileged white people get to draw this neat little circle.
圈子里的每一个人都是正常的
And everyone insidethe circle is normal.
圈子外的人应该被打击 摧毁 重整,再纳入圈子
Everyone outside the circle should be beaten,broken,and reset so they can be broughtinto the circle.
万一失败 就等着送进收容院吧
Failing that,they should be institutionalized.
或者更糟 被怜悯
Or worse,pitied.
照你说 为那男孩感到难过 是错的?
So it's wrong to feel sorryfor this little boy?
为什么要感到难过,他能选择逃离荒唐的繁文缛节
Why would you feel sorryfor someone who gets to opt out ofthe inane courteous formalities
虚假且毫无意义的 这令人羞耻么?
which are utterly meaningless,insincere,and therefore degrading?
这孩子无需假装关心你的背痛 屎尿,或者你祖母哪里痒痒
This kid doesn't have to pretend to be interested in your back pain,or your excretions,or your grandma'sitchy place.
摆脱教人麻木的的社会礼节,生活是何等释放?
Can you imaginehow liberating it would be to live a life freeof all the mind-numbing social niceties?
我不怜悯那孩子
I don't pity this kid.
我嫉妒他
I envy him.
不是癌症
Uh,no cancer.
因为...
Because...
这些不是淋巴细胞
These aren'tlymph cells.
那是什么?
Then what are they?
肝细胞
Liver cells.
臂下的肝细胞
Liver cells under his arm.
好奇肝的原位置有什么?
Wonder what he's got wherehis liver's supposed to be.
为什么肝细胞会跑到小孩的腋窝下?
Anyone got a clue how liver cells got into the kid's armpit?
就当成自己家
Make yourself at home.
也许格氏解剖学完全搞错了?
So,you think maybe gray's anatomy got it all wrong?
淋巴液循环 并不转移器官细胞
Lymph system circulates fluid,not organ cells.
癌细胞总是可以强行进入淋巴系统
Cancer cells break into thelymphatic system all the time.
不是讨论癌细胞
But we're not talkingabout cancer cells.
癌细胞和肝细胞有什么不同?
What's the difference between cancer cellsand liver cells?
为什么一个可以通过内壁 另一个却不能?
Why can one pass through walls but the other can't?
癌细胞是受损坏的
Cancer cells are damaged.
让它们通过血管
Lets them grow into blood vessels.
去任何要去的地方
Go wherever they want.
- 如果肝细胞被破坏,- 肝脏没被破坏
So if the liver cellsare damaged-- liver isn't damaged.
测试显示正常
The tests were normal.
如果肝细胞被破坏,理论上就有可能穿越进入淋巴系统
So if the liver cellsare damaged,it's theoretically possible to pass into the lymphatic system.
肝脏衰竭可以解释胸膜积液,甚至心脏的问题
Liver failure could also explainpleural effusion,even the heart issues.
肝细胞完好
Liver cells are fine.
他对甲型和乙型肝炎免疫,这小孩难道有无保护性行为或共用针头?
He was immunizedfor hep a and b,and do you really thinkthis kid is having unprotected sexor sharing needles?
爸爸看起来是用套子的
Daddy does seem the typeto use a rubber.
不是病毒性的
So it's not viral.
就只剩下酒精肝硬化
That just leaves"lotta-booze-irrhosis.
这十岁小男孩没有酗酒和肝硬化
" Our ten-year-old boy does nothave a drinking problem or cirrhosis.
House 心脏做超声波检测时,察看了一部分肝-- 没有疤痕
House,when we echoedhis heart,we got a piece of his liver-- there was no scarring.
肝硬化可解释症状
Cirrhosis explainsthe symptoms.
- 心脏  肺,-  字典里查"肝硬化"
Heart problems,lungs-- look up "cirrhosis"in the dictionary.
有疤痕的意思
It means "scarring.
父母没干孩子 或对他下毒
" Parents aren't doingor dosing this kid.
你从何而知?
How would you know that?
孩子不会讲话
Kid can't talk.
我为什么接这案例?
Why'd you thinkI took this case?
他不会泄露结局
He's not gonnagive away the ending.
他们为孩子 放弃了工作
They quit their jobsfor him.
是完美的父母
Yes,they are everything you'd want in a parent.
不幸的是 孩子却一无是处
Unfortunately,their kidis nothing you'd want.
婴儿降生 一切如意
When a baby is born,it's perfect.
小手指 小脚趾
Little fingers,little toes.
胖乎乎 粉嘟嘟
Plump,perfect,pink.
前途不可限量
And brimmingwith unbridled potential.
之后每况愈下
But then it's downhill.
有些下坡更是急降
Some hills steeperthan others.
父母夸耀孩子的成就--
Parents get off on their kids'accomplishments-- bend over and relaX.
可爱
Cute.
陈列奖品的房间 成绩通知单,让听者厌烦
They'll annoy you with trophy rooms and report cards.
孩子画紫色母牛 也会说是对色彩敏锐
Hell,they'll even show youa purple cow and tell you what a keen eyefor color their kid has.
但这孩子...
But this kid...
不会笑 不会拥抱
he doesn't smile,he doesn't hug them,he doesn't laugh.
父母什么都落空了,孩子甚至不能从卡片里挑出橙汁
His parents get nothing--the right to brag that their kid pickedorange juice out of a lineup.
你认为他们给孩子一瓶酒 来摆脱
So you figure theyslip the kid a mickey so they don'thave to deal.
做活检 看是不是肝硬化
Do a biopsyto confirm cirrhosis.
别想麻烦Wilson 他得对付Cuddy
And don't tryand pawn it off on wilson-- he's gonnabe busy with cuddy.
我父母无条件爱我
My parents loved meunconditionally.
出去吧
Get out of here.
禁制令是不是过头了?
Don't you think the restrainingorder's a little much?
他又不是真要和17岁病人发生关系
He's not actuallygoing to have sex with a 17-year-old patient.
他也不是真的要我从垃圾桶里,把染血的地毯掏出来
I didn't thinkhe was gonna ask me to dig a bloodstained carpet out of a dumpster,either.
长远看 这算轻松的
It might be easierin the long run.
停下 为了不让House发现我们?
Are we stopping hereso house doesn't find us?
你想要亲热也行
Unless you wantto make out.
你要我向House的无理取闹妥协?
You want me to surrenderto house's coup?
不 你先发制人...
No,no,you proactivelY...
满足他
give him what he wants.
我用妥协来打败他
I defeat him bysurrendering to him.
他所料不及
He'll never see it coming.
我来出钱
Look,I'll pay for itmyself.
多少 铺一间房的地毯要一千?
What is it,a thousand bucksto carpet a room?
就400
Actually,it's 400.
撤了地毯
Oh--not doing it.
肝组织活检?
Liver biopsy?
还在做
They're doing it now.
怎么样?
How's it going?
跟活检没区别
Like a biopsy.
针 细胞
Needles,cells.
尖叫
Screaming.
粪检发现什么?
What'd you findin the stool sample?
你忙着惹毛Cuddy,说过了 阴性 没有寄生虫
You were too busybothering cuddy,but as discussed,it was negative for parasites.
能出去么?
Can we get out of here?
不是问没发现什么
I didn't askwhat you didn't find.
问粪检发现了什么
I asked what you did findin the stool sample.
大便
Stool.
微量的铁 锌 碳酸钙
And traces of iron,zinc,calcium carbonate.
能走吗?
Can we leave?
干什么?
What's the matter?
你怕她?
You afraid of the man?
太晚了
Too late.
别动我东西
Leave my stuff alone!
15分钟后要见个古根海姆基金会的
You have a meeting witha guggenheim in 15 minutes.
就穿这?
Wearing that?
数到三 就开除你
I'm gonna count to three,and then I'm gonnafire you.
- 一,- 碳酸钙 止泻的?
One--calcium carbonate,that's an antidiarrheal,right?
- 二,- 你觉得有意义吗?
Two.--You think that's significant?
硬大便有意义吗?
You think hard poops is significant?
二点五?
Two and a half?
不准备致命一击 就不要威胁
Never threaten unlessyou're ready to deliver.
显得软弱
Makes you look weak.
还好你没有孩子
Thank god you don'thave children.
Cuddy医生
Dr.Cuddy.
留言
Take a message.
你的病人被送入了心脏外科重症室
Your patient is being rushedto cardiac icu.
唯一能让我离开的
That's like the one thingthat would get me outta here.
你们不能进来
I'm sorry,you can't come in here now.
怎么了?
What's going on?
室颤
He's in v-fib.
闪开
Clear.
充电
Charging.
闪开
Clear.
充电
Charging.
闪开
Clear.
充电
Charging.
闪开
Clear.
暂时稳定
He's stable for the moment.
轻度的心房心室阻滞
First-degree atrialventricular blocK.
好
Okay.
还知道什么?
What else do we know?
肝损坏 胸腔积液损害到肺功能
His liver's damaged;pleural effusion compromised his lung function.
活检没查出肝硬化
biopsy was negativefor cirrhosis.
父母没有下毒
Parents didn't poison their son.
不是肝 心脏 肺
It's not his liver,his heart,or his lungs.
是大便里的碳酸钙
It's the calcium carbonatein his stool.
孩子便秘
Kid was constipated.
大概用药过量了
Parents probablyjust overdid it.
也许没有用药
Or they didn't do it at all.
粉笔里也有碳酸钙
Calcium carbonate's also what's in chalk.
他吃粉笔了
So he ate some chalk.
没有毒- 不会导致胸腔积液
It isn't toxic--sure didn'tcause the pleural effusion.
别想粉笔了
Forget the chalk.
你刚说起粉笔
You just said it wasabout the chalk.
然后 我又说 别想粉笔了
Yes,and then I said,"forget the chalk.
你肯定弄糊涂了
" You must be very confused.
孩子有异食癖
This kid's got pica.
带去自助餐 他会吃了桌子
Take him to a buffet,he's gonna eat the table.
可能是铅涂料
Or lead paint.
血铅含量正常
Level of lead in the bloodwas normal.
毒物检验没发现
His tox screen was clean.
不是找典型的毒药
We're not lookingfor typical poisons.
任何可以放入嘴的
We're looking for anythingthat he can put in his mouth.
火柴 蜘蛛 砖头
Matches,spiders,bricks.
经防腐处理的木材可能含砒霜
Pressure-treated wood used to contain arsenic.
接近了
Even better.
样本?
Hansel?
去姜饼屋取样
Get samples of the gingerbread house.
打包
Bag everything.
来这儿 你会惹麻烦
You could get into a lotof trouble,being here.
我想见你
I wanted to see you.
我知道
Yeah,I got that.
其他人也知道
So did everyone else.
他们认为你跟踪我
They thinkyou're a stalker.
说不定是因你引人注目 遭人嫉妒
One could argue those people might be jealousof your attention.
我也这么争辩
Yes,I actuallymade that argument.
你回家?
You going home?
计划是
That's the plan.
在冰岛 同意性行为年龄是14岁
In iceland,the age of consent is 14.
那儿的旅游业不发达 真教人吃惊
I'm surprised that tourism isn't a bigger industryup there.
今天 我诱人犯罪
So today I'm jailbait.
22个星期后
But in 22 weeks...
就可以对我为所欲为
anybody can do anything to me.
在22个星期里 我变化这么大?
Will I be so differentin 22 weeks?
22周足够让受精卵长出手脚
22 weeks is enoughfor an embryo to grow arms and legs.
只是界线
It's just a line.
一堆穿长袍的老可怜划下的武断界线
An arbitrary line drawn by a bunch of sad,old menin robes.
是
Yeah.
谁在乎法官怎么想?
Who cares what judges think?
看不出你是个循规蹈矩的人
Didn't think of youas a guy who followed rules just becausethey were rules.
你...比我年轻十多岁
You are...over ten years youngerthan me.
我说了 多
I said over.
得走了!
Gotta go!
House.
House
Cuddy医生!
Dr.Cuddy!
知道去冰岛领事馆的路吗?
do you happen to know the way tothe icelandic consulate?
这陌生的姑娘 向我问路
This young woman,a stranger to me,was just asking directions.
保安会叫警察
Security was gonnacall the police.
我不想这么做
I don't wantto do that to you.
回家吧
Go home.
她要搭个车
She needed a ride.
她一人能来 就能一人回去
She got her on her own,she can get home on her own.
马上
Now.
再在医院看见你 我会叫警察
And if I see youon hospital grounds again,i will call the police.
受了那一眼 我觉得生机勃勃
After that look,I'm feeling a little frisky.
看来你也兴奋了
Looks like you're up.
我在排卵 抓紧
I'm ovulating.Let's go.
生机勃勃的感觉 没了
The frisky,it went away.
House 别当儿戏
House,this isn't a game.
要是我不理她 能要回地毯吗?
If I leave her alone,can I have my carpet back?
不行
No.
要是放弃地毯 能要她吗?
If I forget about my carpet,can I have her?
曼陀罗
Jimsonweed.
在后院发现一小片
Found a small patch of it in his backyard.
曼陀罗含颠茄碱
Jimsonweed contains atropine.
穷人的迷幻药
Poor man's acid.
孩子随 "露丝在天空与氧化皓做伴"蹒跚,(甲壳虫名曲)
Our kid's been tripping on lucy in the sky with cubic zirconia.
能解释胸腔积液 心律不齐
Explains the pleural effusion,the heart arrhythmias.
在这里会诊 不会让Cuddy心烦
Meeting here will do nothingto upset cuddy.
我不想惹Cuddy心烦
I'm not tryingto upset cuddy.
在找病因
I'm trying to figure outwhat's wrong with the patient.
继续
Continue.
说完了
I'm done.
曼陀罗没法解释尖叫
Jimsonweed doesn't explainthe screaming.
你大概没经历过糟糕的旅行
You've obviously neverhad a bad trip.
一举两得
I would've thought you'd try to accomplishtwo goals at once.
你怎么就不像其他暗恋我的非适龄女生?
Why can't you be more like the other age-inappropriate girls who have a thing for me?
接受我的原样
Just accept me for me.
继续
Continue.
治疗曼陀罗中毒要用毒扁豆碱
Treatment for jimsonweed od is physostigmine.
孩子心脏有病
Kid's got heart issues.
不能调和
The two don't mix.
得先确认他的病因
We'd better make sure that's what he's got.
从帕特森的实验室运血清过来,至少要3天
Serum from the lab in paterson is three days,minimum.
他坚持不了三天
He won't survive three days.
他几点起床?
What time does he wake up?
上午7:35
7:35 am.
然后呢?
Then what?
一一说来
Walk me through it.
7:40到7:50 去了洗手间洗脸
7:40 to 7:50,he goes tothe toilet,washes his face.
有必要吗?
What does this matter?
我要证明他吃了植物
I'm trying to provehe ate the plant.
他的日程和曼陀罗无关
His schedule has nothingto do with jimsonweed.
有两种可能性 要么,他父母看着他吃下植物
There are two possibilities--either the parents saw him eat the plant,
要么在没人看顾时 不玩积木 吃了植物
or the kid has unsupervised time and eats plants insteadof playing with blocks.
就算找出15分钟的户外自由活动,也证明不了他吃草
Even if you find 15 minutesof free time outside,doesn't mean he spent iteating a bush.
该怎么办?
So what do we do?
什么也不做?
Nothing?
等孩子告诉我们?
Wait for the kidto tell us?
说呀
What?
你干什么?
Where are you going?
跟他谈谈
To talk to him.
见过你孩子吃植物吗?
Ever see your son eat a bush?
没有
I haven'T.
只看过他吃--
I've only ever seen himeat what--
Adam 你在家吃了些东西
adam,you ate something at your house.
让你生病
Something that made you sick.
我要你告诉我吃的是什么
I need you to show mewhat you ate.
他没法回答你
He can't answer you.
你也不行
Neither can you.
这是你家的后院
This is your backyard.
你也许把那当作梅尔快餐店
You may know itas mel's diner.
这是你的沙盒
This is your sandbox.
游戏场
Your jungle gym.
下面有这个
And under it is this.
你有没有吃了这个 Adam
I need to knowif you ate this,adam.
他不知道你想要什么
He doesn't know what you want.
Adam 你必须告诉我
Adam,you have to tell me.
如果你不说...
Because if you don'T...
游戏就要结束了
It'll be game over.
- 你会死的,- 你到底在干什么?
You'll be dead.--What the hellare you doing?
指给我看你吃的东西
show me what you ate.
Adam.
Adam
指给我看你吃的东西
Show me what you ate.
沙盒
sandbox
- Adam?,- 亲爱的?
Adam?--Honey?
Adam.
Adam
快进来 兄弟姐妹!
Come on in,brothers and sister!
欢迎来到上帝之家
Welcome to the houseof the lord.
House 有没有搞错
house,come on.
在礼拜堂?
The chapel?
被赐予了新的症状 一个奇迹
We have been blessed with the miracleof a new symptom.
兄弟 能否查出可怜孩子的眼球为何回滚?
Brother,can you testifyas to why this poor child's eyeball rolled back into his head?
和曼陀罗的毒性一致 眼球麻痹
It's consistent with jimsonweedpoisoning--ocular paralysis.
对不起
Sorry.
邪恶欺骗汝等 他们背弃了上帝 愚蠢啊
The wicked shall deceive ye,because they have turned from the lord and are idiots.
眼肌不是麻痹了,而是在作皮鲁埃特旋转
His ocular muscle didn't paralyze,it pirouetted.
多发性硬化症
M.S.
睿智之人更易进入天堂
It is easier for a wise man to gain access to heaven
能不能停下? 直说不是多发性硬化症好了
will you stop doing that?Just say "not M.S.
中风
a stroke.
颅内出血
Bleed in the brain.
除了单眼位移 还会看到别的症状
We'd be seeingother symptoms besides a single eye misalignment.
比如昏迷
Like a coma.
已经查证过了
And you've already testified.
是肿瘤
it's a tumor.
所有的成像都没显示出来?
And all the imagingjust missed it?
微瘤
It's a microtumor.
原发于肺 导致胸腔积液
Started in his lung,which caused the pleural effusion.
然后转至肝 使肝细胞脱落
Then it metastasizedto his liver,which made it slough cells.
再到大脑 眼球的后方,导致眼球回滚
And then went to his brain,behind the eye,which caused it to roll back into his head.
这么说他有三个肿瘤 全漏诊了
So he has three tumorsand we missed all of them.
奇迹的反面是什么?
What's the opposite of a miracle?
知道从哪里下手 找起来希望就大了
I have a better chanceof finding it now that I knowexactly where to look.
那么...
So...
除非有更好的主意 我要给他大脑做CT了
unless you have a better idea,I'm gonna go ct his head.
然后 如果--有必要 我会移除他的眼球
And then,if--if I have to,remove his eye.
把这孩子的眼球摘除 ,少了眼神接触 孩子情况更糟
You remove this kid's eye,he's only gonna behalf as good at not making eye contact.
嗨?
hello?
Hello?
嗨?
告诉你个不好的消息
I have sad news for you.
她不爱你
She doesn't love you.
你嫉妒的时候真丑
You're uglywhen you're jealous.
她昨晚上我家了
She showed up at my houselast night.
冲我来的
Came on to me.
比想象的还要完美
She's even more perfectthan I thought.
House.
House
她有病
She's sick.
你说"有病" 我认为"开放"
You say "sick,"I say "freestylin'.
那女孩会和软体动物做爱
" The girl will have sexwith an invertebrate.
不会吧
Come on.
你没那么差劲
You're not that bad.
她有问题
She has a problem.
纵容她无益
You're not doing her any favorsby indulging her.
你为什么撒谎?
Why would you lielike this?
心里没有为爱留一点空间?
Do you not have room your heart for love?
你不相信我
You don't believe me.
当孩子说Susie和Johnny一起睡觉时,我不信
I didn't believe the kids when they said that susiewas sleeping with johnny.
过去不信 现在也不信
I didn't believe them then,I don't believe them now.
才不管Susie有没有和Johnny结婚--,他是我的
I don't care that susiemarried johnny--he's mine.
她右边的乳房有个胎记 就在乳头下
She has a mole on her right breast,just below the nipple.
不 她没有
No,she doesn'T.
你连她乳房都看过了?
You've seen her breasts?
是个医学检查
It was a medical exam.
我当时对她的心脏进行听诊
I was listeningto her heart.
就听到了,Greg-House Greg-House Greg-House
It went,"greg-house,greg-house,greg-house.
好吧 我撒了谎
" Fine,I'm lying.
不过她确实跑回来了
But she did come back.
锁在我办公室里
She's locked upin my office.
我希望你能和她谈谈
I was hopingyou could talk to her.
了结这件事
Put an end to this.
听我说
Listen to me.
知道和我在一起 有什么指望吗?
Do you have any idea whatyou'd have to look forward to if you stayed with me?
十之八九我俩都会进监狱
Nine chances out of ten,we'd both wind up in a jail.
你那么说 只是想让我走
You're only saying thatto make me go.
因为那是真的
I'm saying it'cause it's true.
我们心里都知道 你该和Victor在一起
Inside of us,we both knowthat you belong with victor.
你班上有叫Victor的吗?
Is there a victorin your class?
如果你不和年龄相仿的人在一起,会后悔的
If you're not withsomeone your age,you'll regret it.
就在不久的将来
Maybe not today,maybe not tomorrow,but soon.
而且后悔终身
And for the restof your life.
那我们呢?
What about us?
我们能想象弗雷斯诺,(加州一城市)
We'll always have fresno.
我不善于表现得高尚
I'm no good at being noble,
这个疯狂的世界 ,微小的你我无法以卵击石
but it doesn'ttake much to see that the problems of two little people dot amount to a hill of beans in this crazy world.
有一天 你会明白
Someday you'llunderstand that.
好了 好了
Now,now.
看看你...
Here's looking at you...
该死
damn.
你在弗雷斯诺时 有没有发生过地震?
Was there an earthquakewhen you were in fresno?
什么?
What?
我问每个女朋友那个问题
I ask all my girlfriends that.
是的 一次小的
yeah,a little one.
该死
Damn.
什么?
What?
什么 你说什么?
What,what is it?
那不是爱
It's not love.
你大脑里有个孢子
You have a sporein your brain.
粗球孢子菌
Coccidioides immitis.
加州到处都是
California's full of 'em.
地震了一下 孢子释放到空气中,你吸入 然后感冒...
They get an earthquake,they get released into the air,you breathe it in,you get a cold...
表现为窦腔充血 头痛 身体虚弱...
turns into sinus congestion,aches,weakness...
牛奶泪...
milky tears...
有时还...
and sometimes...
还会失去克制力和判断力
a loss of inhibition and judgment.
真该死!
Damn!
所以...
So...
爱上你?
loving you?
想和你做爱?
Wanting to have sexwith you?
这些都只是...
It was all just...
受孢子左右?
the spores talking?
你能活下来
You'll probably live.
该死
Damn.
嘿!
Hey!
别碰他的眼睛
Don't touch his eye.
这是阑尾切除术
This is an appendectomy.
一样 别碰他的眼睛
Like i said,don't touch his eye.
他怎么没有手术?
Why isn't he in surgery?
有急诊病人抢先了
Well,some emergencybumped him.
十分钟后 就有手术室
We've got another room in ten minutes.
不要送他进去了
You're not taking him in.
关灯
Kill the lights.
他一直看到它们
He was seeing themall the time.
你在找什么?
What are you looking for?
他一直告诉我们 看到的是什么
And he was telling uswhat he was seeing.
告诉我们 到底出了什么问题
Telling us exactlywhat was wrong with him.
一遍又一遍地描绘
Drawing them for usover and over again.
没人懂孤独症孩子说话的方式
Nobody knewhow to speak "autistic.
当我问他吃了什么时 他告诉了我答案
" When I asked him what he ate,he even told me that.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
他一直看到的是什么?
What was he seeing?
你们好 小美人儿
Hello,my pretties.
不是肿瘤 Foreman
It's not a tumor,foreman.
是蠕虫
It's worms.
正在他眼睛里游着呢
Swimming in his eye.
动物把沙盒当做便盆
Animal makes pottyin the sandbox.
小男孩在沙盒里玩 吃了沙子
Boy plays in the sandbox,boy eats the sand.
之后的情节都清楚了
You can probably tellwhere this is going by now.
粪检寄生虫呈阴性
Stool samples were negativefor parasites.
浣熊蛔虫不会被人类宿主排泄
Raccoon roundworms are not excreted by their human host.
Cameron检测了沙子
Cameron tested the sand.
全部都检测了?
All of it?
蠕虫从消化道扩散到其他部分
Worms spread from his gutto the rest of his body.
侵袭了他的肺
They attacked his lungs.
让他喊叫 体液渗出
That's what made him screamand caused the effusion.
侵入了肝 使死亡的肝细胞随淋巴液流动
They invade his liver,sending dead liver cells coursing through his system.
又攻击了他的眼球和环肌,使眼球向后翻筋斗
They attack his eyeand the muscles surrounding it,making his eyeballdo a backflip.
激光光凝治疗眼球 ,大剂量的苯并咪唑杀虫
Laser photocoagulation to fix the eye and a high doseof benzimidazole to kill the worms.
等一下
Wait a minute.
就这样了?
That's it?
他- 他会好吗?
H-he's gonna be okay?
好消息
Good news.
他会和你们在一起很久
He's gonna be with youfor a long,long time.
我给你读些东西
I'm going to read you something.
艾斯伯格症候群是一种,温和但罕见的孤独症
"Asperger's syndrome isa mild and rare form of autism.
典型表现为 很难与同伴建立友谊和玩乐
"It is typically characterized by difficulty "establishing friendshipsand playing with peers,
难以接受社会惯例,讨厌改变既定日程或布置
"trouble accepting convential social rules,"and they dislike any change in setting or routine.
或宽幅地毯
" Or broadloom.
没说最后那部分 但你懂这意思
It doesn't saythat last part,but you get my point.
House不是艾斯伯格症候群
House doesn't have asperger'S.
诊断要简单得多
The diagnosisis much simpler.
他就是个混蛋
He's a jerk.
他为什么会接这个病例?
Why do you thinkhe took this case?
因为他相信这对父母?
Because he believesthese parents?
他想救一个小男孩?
Because he wants to helpa young boy?
他透过这个孩子看到了自己
He sees himself in this kid.
他是在拯救他自己
And he's tryingto help himself.
他也不想这样
He doesn't want this.
他必须
He needs it.
你不是孤独症
You're not autistic.
连艾斯伯格症候群也不是
You don't evenhave asperger'S.
你希望你是
You wish you did.
可以使你免除规矩的约束
It would exempt youfrom the rules.
获得自由 免除责任
Give you freedom,absolve you of responsibility.
好让你和17岁的女孩约会
Let you date 17-year-olds.
更重要的是 意味着你不是一个混蛋
But most important,it would mean that you're not just a jerk.
无休止地教训别人,到什么程度 ,会让他自己变混蛋?
At what point does a person endlessly lecturing someone make him a jerk?
最初的湿吻...
Your first tongue kiss...
是八分的快乐
an eight on the happiness scale.
孩子死里逃生...
Your child being snatched backfrom the brink of death...
才是十分的
that's a ten.
但他们只表现出不愠不火的六分半
But they're clocking inat a very tepid 6.5,
因为知道回去的生活是老样子
because they know whatthey have to go back to.
嗯...
Uh,listen...
谢谢
thanks.
你救了他的命
You saved his life.
是 我知道
Yeah,I know.
再会
See ya.
太棒了
That was so good.
那才是十分的快乐
That was a ten.
改变都是不好的吗?
All change is bad?
不是真的 你知道
It's not true,you know.